Ian Fleshman-Cooper

Monroe, WA 98272 | Phone: (425) 495-3453 | Email: ian.fleshmancooper@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-fleshman-cooper/

Portfolio: https://ianfleshmancooper.com

Summary

BA and Summa Cum Laude honors in Mathematics and IT from Northwest University. Certificate in Full-stack web development from the University of Washington and a certificate in Instructional Design for eLearning. I am currently a Digital Learning Specialist for the Monroe School District where I educate students in computer science as well as help assist other staff and faculty in enhancing their curriculum through tech integration. Previously, I had been an Academic Advisor for Northwest University for three years, with valuable experience in solving solutions to create efficiency, consultant for students, and collaborate with/train a team of advisors to reach team goals. Through this position, I was a part of the developmental team in which we consult, develop, and update software to help with system maintenance and data tracking. With a drive to learn and proven experience as a reliable team player and supportive leader, I am looking to serve and help others achieve goals through efficiency and simplicity.

Technical Skills

Applications: Office 365, Teams, Canvas LMS, Clever LMS, Skyward, iOS, Nearpod, PowerCampus, MS Access, Google Suite, Salesforce, Photoshop, WeVideo, Wondershare Filmora, Terminal, GitHub, GitBash, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, JSON, Bootstrap, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Heroku

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React, SQL, Ruby

Experience

Digital Learning Specialist Monroe School District

2021 - Current

Monroe, WA

Educate students in Washington state standards for Computer Science. This curriculum included subjects in digital citizenship, coding, typing, robotics, as well as algorithms and computational thinking. This job has provided much experience in classroom management as well as instructional design for virtual and classroom settings.

• While designing lesson plans, I would utilize and administer Learning Management Systems such as Canvas and Clever to keep track of student progress as well as student resources.

Outside of teaching, my responsibilities are to help strengthen other staff and faculty by enhancing their lessons/curriculum through technology integration. This would sometimes require coaching and training other staff or students to use certain technologies in order to help them find more simplicity and efficiency in their work.

• This district mainly utilizes the Google suite for its platform in communication and system management.

NPP Academic Advisor Northwest University

2018 - 2021

Kirkland, WA

Assist students with a plan for their higher education. Consult with students and staff and manage tasks and data systems. Familiarity with many software applications such as Excel, Access, PowerCampus, Salesforce, Calendly, Office 365, Teams, and Zoom.

• Gained valuable experience in establishing leadership as I was involved in training and managing new team members. I also had the privilege to develop and maintain systems which were key for data tracking, efficiency, and keeping up with quarterly goals.

Technology Assistant Sultan School District

2017 - 2018

Sultan, WA

Provided help desk support for troubleshooting solutions. Repaired computers by replacing keyboards, screens, hard drives, Wi-Fi chips, and performing reimages. Rearranged classrooms and set up/tore down computer areas. Gained experience repairing projectors and smart boards.

Paraprofessional Sultan School District

2014 - 2018

Sultan, WA

Support children and teens in their learning through encouragement, brainstorming for ideas, social expectations, as well as relationship building. Classroom management, communication with students and their parents, and tutoring and one-on-one support.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Business Administration IT: Northwest University - Kirkland, WA | Summa Cum Laude – Annual Dean's List

Instructional Design for eLearning Certificate: Udemy Instructor - Marina Arshavskiy Udemy program that covered methodology, skills, and techniques necessary for developing effective eLearning solutions. This includes the process of analyzing data and learning objectives, designing and developing course content, implementing the content to audiences, and finally comparing learning progress to measurable standards.

Full- Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Washington – Seattle, WA 24-week intensive program gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React JS, MongoDB, Node.JS as well as going in depth with Algorithms, Efficiency, and Data Structures.